So let's come over to our code.
We will know that. So we're going to
uncomment this code. This code right
here is our counter. And I'm going to
rename it to arrow
at the arrow position. So that's our
number at the arrow position. What we
want to do is we want to start another
loop inside of this loop that repeats
itself. So this loop is going to repeat
another loop. So we'll start with a four
and then we're going to say let
and then we're going to call this one
box. And we're going to say the box that
we're comparing is equal to wherever the
arrow is plus one. Because if we come
over to our slideshow,
when we start our comparison on each
round, so right after we've moved the
arrow, we move the arrow. What box do we
compare? The one right next to it.
We move the arrow. What box do we
compare? The one right next to it. So
that much we know. So we want it to
compare the one right next to it. So
we've said we want to start the box
counter at wherever the arrow counter is
plus one.
That's where we want it to start. How
long do we want it to go? Well, that's
really easy. It's just the end um of the
array because if you watch which box we
compare before we move the arrow again,
we always look at the last box in the
array. Okay? So, that means we need our
box counter to go all the way to the
last one in the array. So we'll come
here and we'll say let's go until box is
less than numbers.length.
And then we'll increment box as we
slowly move down the array.
So we will know this works if box starts
at 1
and goes 1 2 3 4 5 and then starts at 2
and goes 2 3 4 5 and then starts at
three goes 3 4 5 and then four five and
then five. So let's just console.log
that
because that's talking about the
position in the array. We'll console.log
box and we'll go look at our code. So,
we'll come over here to Safari. Come to
our console. We'll reload. And we get 1
2 3 4 5
5 2 3 4 5 6 and oh, sorry. I think I
have another log. Ah, we have a log
right here. Let's get rid of that. Save
it. Come back over.
Come to our console. We'll reload. We
get 1 2 3 4 5 2 3 4 5 3 4 5 and then
four and then five. And then just five.
So, if we go over to here and look at
where the box compares, we're going to
go all the way back to the beginning of
this array.
The box starts in position
01. So, the box starts at position index
one, then index two, then index three,
then index four, then index five, and
then
index 2, 3, 4, 5.
3 4 5 and then three four five
and then
four or sorry and then five and then it
was done.
So, because we have successfully logged
out those numbers, we now know that our
box will store the position that we're
comparing.